This one's a good one. How do you think
TRT treatment will evolve over the next
5 to 10 years? Any new science to look
out for in optimization? So, when I was
in the US, I met the owner of a company
called Kaiser who are making an oral
version of testosterone. Um, so there
are continued innovations in the field.
Uh, recently people have also been
talking about a nasal delivery option as
well. Um, both of these options have
drawbacks and limitations. Um, and even
when speaking with uh with with with
Kaiser, and I'm sure in the future he'd
love to come on this channel and talk
about the product, too. I can be happy
to link that up. Um, they recognize that
they will not replace injectables and
and topical cream. It's more so they're
adding another option to the market. Um,
when it comes to the future of
treatment,
ideally the things that I'd love to see,
I'd love to see an eststerized version
of luteinizing hormone. I think that
would be great if we could inject, you
know, eststerized LH and FSH with
testosterone. That would that would be
fantastic. Then we wouldn't have to have
this whole hCG discussion. Um, that
would be cool. Um, I don't know if
that'll happen, but I imagine the future
will be finding a way that we can
optimize levels without shutting down
natural production. Um, that's the
that's I think if if people are going to
innovate further, that'll be the thing
that innovates. I think the next chapter
for TRT, and again, I don't gamble, but
I'd probably bet money on this. when
testosterone undeenoate which is known
as riandrin or nido when that becomes
generic I think that's going to not
completely replace an nanthad and
cypionate but basically with nibido they
say you can do one shot every 3 months
and have stable levels if that was the
case you know four jabs a year that
would be great it doesn't work like that
but they also said that you could do one
shot of an nanthate or cypionate every 2
to 3 weeks
That didn't work out either. But if we
could do a shot of undecinate every week
and get the same stability as doing
daily injections of cpionate and the
undeinoate is still 200 or 250 milligram
per mill if that became generically
available I think that's going to be the
next thing. So in the next five or 10
years when testosterone undecinate8
becomes generic, I think weekly shots of
that for stability, I think that will be
the next uh step for injectable
testosterone. But I also think we're
going to see a significant increase in
the popularity of the transcrotal cream.
Um I think Dr. Keith Nichols has kind of
spearheaded and you know he's been
talking about this stuff for years and
his content has aged really well on it.
um as well as you Stephen I mean you've
been talking about this for a long time
too and um I think that cream is going
to become more and more popular purely
because more people are discovering that
in practice it works really well and I
think that's that says a lot I mean we
can have mechanistic theory and ideas
and studies about stuff but in practice
the cream works really well and it works
really well for people who don't respond
well to injections and I think that's a
pretty remarkable thing So, I'd also
recommend people check out Neil
Ruseier's new book. It's called Hormones
Demystified. I've got a copy of it
around here somewhere, but it's a very
layman's book. It's an easy read. Um,
and if people want to learn more about
the future of men's HRT, I think that
more going into the full hormone
optimization, so beyond TRT, which is
the title of my book, but this kind of
stuff that Neil's been talking about
through World Link, Steven's been using
it for a while, Keith's been talking
about it for a while, going looking
beyond TRT, but in terms of, you know,
optimizing things like melatonin,
thyroid, bringing alone DHEA, I think
this is also going to be a big part of
the future of it as